While distributed computing and big-data applications have existed for a long time,
尽管分布式计算和大数据应用已经存在很久了
most people associate the recent big-data boom
绝大多数人仍会认为最近的大数据潮与
with the emergence of the Hadoop Ecosystem.
Hadoop 生态系统的出现有关
We will take a look at the backbones of Hadoop and talk a
我们先来了解 Hadoop 的主要构成
bit about the related technologies you might come across.
然后讲些相关技术
But as David mentioned at the beginning,
但就像 David 刚开始提到的那样
the ecosystem is fairly complex and you definitely don't
整个生态系统非常复杂
need to know all these tools to get started with Spark.
你并不需要了解所有知识来学习 Spark
Doug Cutting and Mike Cafarella co-founded the open source Hadoop framework in
Hadoop 开源框架是由Doug Cutting 和 Mike Cafarella 在2006 年共同搭建的
2006 based on previous Google Research published in the early 2000s.
该框架来源于 Google 在 2000 年初发表的论文
The Hadoop framework consists of four main components.
Hadoop 框架包括  4 个主要部分
The first is the Hadoop Distributed File System or HDFS in short.
第一部分是 Hadoop 分布式文件系统 简称 HDFS
HDFS stores data on commodity machines with application,
HDFS  把数据存储在带应用程序的商用机集群上
hence providing very high aggregate bandwidth across the cluster.
这样系统可以给整个集群提供非常高的总体带宽
The second is Hadoop MapReduce an implementation
第二部分, Hadoop MapReduce
of the MapReduce programming model for large scale data processing.
是一个MapReduce 编程模型在处理大规模数据的应用程序
Most people think of this,
绝大多数人提到 MapReduce 时
when they think of MapReduce.
指的就是这个
The third is a resource manager called Hadoop YARN,
第三部分是个叫做 Hadoop YARN  的资源管理器
that schedules the computation over code of users applications.
它会负责为用户程序调度运算资源
Finally, Hadoop Common contains libraries and utilities needed by other Hadoop modules.
最后一部分是 Hadoop Common  它包含了Hadoop其他组件需要的工具和库
Soon after the MapReduce projects started,
MapReduce 项目刚开始不久
other projects began to provide higher-level abstraction on top of this Java Framework.
其他项目就开始用这个 Java 框架搭建更高级的东西
Apache Pig for example,
比如Apache Pig
was developed by Yahoo to allow researchers to run
就是由 Yahoo开发的一个平台
Ad hoc MapReduce jobs using a language similar to SQL.
研究者可以用类似 SQL 的语言在平台上跑 MapReduce 任务
Apache Hive, is another tool that provides
Apache Hive 是另一个
higher level interface for SQL data summarization, query, and analysis.
提供用 SQL 做数据总结、查询和分析的高级界面
The problem with the traditional MapReduce approach is that after each step,
传统 MapReduce 方法有个问题
the results are saved to disk.
每一步之后的结果都存在了硬盘中
If you remember the previous videos,
如果你还记得上一个视频
Disk ayo is relatively so,
硬盘非常慢
so these jobs can take too long.
所以这个过程就会非常耗时
The slowness motivated Matei Zaharia to start
这就促使了Matei Zaharia 于 2009年
disbarred project at UC Berkeley's AmpLab in 2009.
开始在 UC Berkeley 的 AmpLab 做 disbarred 项目
Spark doesn't have to write intermediate results to disk and can perform
Spark 不用把中间结果写入硬盘
fast in-memory computations for multiple Map and Reduce steps.
在Map 和 Reduce 的过程都可以在内存中完成
The projects has open source in 2010 and became a top-level Apache project in 2014.
这个项目在2010年开源 而后在2014年成为了一个顶级 Apache 项目
Since then, it's popularity and adaptation has been growing steadily.
从那以后 其流行度和适应性与日俱增
There are two other distributed streaming
还有另外两种分布式计算流
processing projects that started around the same time as Spark,
差不多和 Spark 同时进行
and later became top-level Apache projects, Storm and Flink.
后来变成了顶级 Apache 项目 Storm 和 Flink
Storm was originally created by Nathan Marz,
Storm 是Nathan Marz 开发的
where he was at a social media startup called BackType.
当时他在一家叫BackType 的创业公司工作
Twitter later acquired BackType and open sourced Storm.
Twitter 后来收购了BackType 并将Storm开源了
Flink started as a collaboration between German universities and research institutes.
Flink 始于德国高校和研究机构的合作
Both tools are designed for fast streaming,
两个工具都是为了高速计算数据流
so you can get results in milliseconds,
你可以在毫秒级时间内获取结果
which is much shorter than you can accomplish with Spark's streaming library.
这个方式比 Spark的数据流计算库要快的多